这一定是古人守卫亚特兰蒂斯的
最后一道防线
It must be the Ancients last line of
defence before Atlantis
在古人最后的抵抗中被攻破了
Knocked out during the Ancients
last stand?
它的能源耗尽了
一万年可是一段很长的时间
It's power source is depleted. 10,000
years is a long time.
有一艘不明飞船, 大小近似于幽灵的梭镖飞船
正向城市飞来
There's an unidentified craft, about the size
of a Wraith dart, heading for the city.
它在做什么?
What's it doing?
扫描我们
It's scanning us.
那些是什么?
What are those?
幽灵的母船, 3艘
Wraith Hive ships. 3 of them.
如果保持方向和速度
两周后它们将会到达我们的星球
If they maintain direction and speed,they'll
be over our planet within two weeks.
幽灵在你的祖先身上进行实验
The Wraith were conducting experiments
on your ancestors.
你有部分幽灵的DNA
You have some Wraith DNA
她能看到发生了什么么?
Can she see what's happening?
我在一艘飞船上
I am on a ship.
我在某种控制室中
I am in some sort of control room.
你们都是如此的可怜!
You are all so pathetic!
我觉得这不是Teyla在说话
Something tells me that's not
Teyla talking.
有可能是Teyla将我们的
阿尔法站点的位置告诉给了幽灵
Then chances are it was Teyla who gave away
the location of our Alpha Site to the Wraith.
它们知道亚特兰蒂斯是唯一通往
一个全新的, 富饶的取食场的通道
They know that Atlantis is the only way to
get to a new rich feeding ground.
地球
Earth.
除了Teyla之外, 我们现在都可以确定
幽灵更感兴趣的
Not only has Teyla been able to
ascertain that the Wraith
是地球, 而不是亚特兰蒂斯
你们知道, 这很恐怖
are more interested in Earth, than Atlantis,
which is, you know, terrifying.
她知道了幽灵的母船会正好经过
She realised that the hive
ships will go right past
唯一幸存的Le Grandia卫星
the only surviving
Le Grandia point satellite
我们可以想象
在那个硕果仅存的卫星所在的地方
The last of what we assume,
where dozens of defense satellites destroyed
还有数十个防御卫星
在古人抵抗幽灵的战斗中被摧毁了
during the Ancients last stand
with the Wraith.
是的, 是的, 是的
Yes, yes, yes.
现在的想法是, 我们可以利用这个卫星
The point is, we think
we can use it to our advantage.
我想你以前曾经说过它已经没有用了
I thought you said it was dead.
确实是, 不过我想如果我们搞清楚了
它是如何工作的, 还是可以把它修好的
It is, but we think we learned enough
about how it works, to bring it back.
如果我们知道它到底出了什么问题
If we are right about what is wrong with it.
是的, 当然, 如果我们知道
它到底是出了什么问题
Yes of course if we're right about
what's wrong with it.
但即便是我们是对的, 可是它却没有足够的能量
幽灵还是可以对它熟视无睹
But if we're right, and it's just out of power,
the Wraith have simply been ignoring it.
根据我们的初步估计
只用一台naquadah发电机
Our preliminary estimates indicate,
a single naquadah generator,
就足够可以让它继续工作
would be enough to bring it back online.
我们为什么不能用我们的发电机
让亚特兰蒂斯的武器系统工作起来呢?
Why can't we use our generators to get
the weapon systems of Atlantis working?
因为这些系统本来是设计从
零点模块来提取能量的
Because those systems were designed
to be powered by the Zero Point Module,
而卫星却不是
and the satellite isn't.
你的意思是, 你认为它还不够强大
足以干掉一艘幽灵的母船
You mean, you don't think it's powerful
enough to take out a Wraith hive ship.
根据古人的数据库
当完全充满电时
Well, according to the Ancient database,
it should be able to
它应该能够干掉所有这三艘母船
take out all three,
when fully charged.
请记住古人的科技比幽灵要远远先进
Keep in mind that the Ancient
technology was far superior.
他们输掉那场战争
仅仅是因为幽灵的数目太多了
They only lost the war
because they were vastly outnumbered.
对我们来说
幽灵同样也是占了数量上的优势
We're vastly outnumbered.
而且武器也比我们好
And outgunned.
但是它们还没有看到卫星的力量
But they don't see
the satellite as strength
用军方的说法
In military parlance?
出其不意, 是对我们有利的一个因素
Surprise, is an element on our side.
你需要什么?
What do you need?
乘坐我们的小飞船, 需要15小时
才能到达那颗卫星
The satellite is 15 hours away,
by Puddle Jumper.
我建议我们组织一个小分队
I recommend that we
put together a small crew.
包括我, Grodin和一个飞行员
Say myself,
Grodin and a pilot.
我会去
I'll go.
不用, 让Miller去就可以了
No, Miller can handle it.
少校, 我希望你继续搜索阿尔法站点
Major, I need you to keep searching
for alternate Alpha Sites,
以防万一卫星也失败了
just in case this fails.
母船在49小时之后就会进入
卫星的攻击范围
The hive ships will be in range
of the satellite in forty nine hours.
我们需要充分利用这其中的每一秒钟
We're gonna need every last second,
of that time.
还有什么问题么?
Questions?
好吧, 我们开始干吧
Ok, let's get on it.
Rodney
Well Rodney.
我并不是想给你增加压力
不过此时此刻
Don't mean to put any undue pressure,
but at this moment,
那个卫星是唯一可以在幽灵和亚特兰蒂斯之间
起抵抗作用的东西了
that satellite is the only thing standing
between the Wraith and Atlantis.
不要压力过大
No undue pressure?
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第19集 围攻 第一部分
StarGate Atlantis
1x19 - The Siege
我没事
I'm fine
我看你有些太心急了
I'm looking for something
a little more enthusiastic, than fine.
我已经准备好回去执行任务了
I'm ready to be put back
on active duty.
我知道你是这样想的
不过...
I'm sure you think so,
but uh...
告诉他我没事
Tell him I'm fine.
她没说错, 少校
She is Major.
我觉得没有理由
再让她在这里接受医学监护了
I see no further reason she should be
kept here under medical supervision.
好吧, 你可以回去参加任务了
Alright, you're back on active duty.
我认为我自己可以处理这个!
I think I can handle this alone!
你没有别的事要去做的么?
Isn't there something better
you should be doing?
我认为我应该去
I think I should go.
是的, 我同意
Yes, I agree.
走吧!
Go!
我的意思是, 参加这次任务
I mean, on the mission.
为什么?
Why?
是的, 你可能比我更了解那个卫星
Sure, you probably know a little bit
more about the satellite than I do.
你终于注意到这一点了?
Noticed that have you?
但是你对这个城市的了解
要比我多得多
But you know a lot more about
the city than I do.
好吧, 我知道该如何取舍
Ok, I think I see where this is going now.
不管是什么原因
如果那边发生了什么状况
For whatever reason,
if there is problem there,
那应该是我, 不是你
it should be me, not you.
那里不会有问题的
There's not going to be a problem.
- Rodney, 你不知道
- 如果....
Rodney, you don't know that.
If....
如果我们无法修好它
我们就掉头回来
If it seems like we can't fix it,
we'll just turn around and come back.
现在我知道了
我在每个地方都是无价之宝...
Now I realise I am invaluable everywhere...
你知道么?
You know what?
当我没说!
Forget about it!
我收回刚才说的话
I take it back.
别!
No!
抱歉!
不要!
Sorry!
Nope!
你无法收回刚才所说的话, 因为你已经承认了
我比你更加聪明
You can't take it back, because you've just
admitted that I am smarter than you are.
我并没有承认这一点!
I admitted no such thing!
你可能很难说出口
在你刚才强迫自己说那番话的时候
It was hard for you to say,
but the truth shone through,
所要表达的意思已经昭然若揭了
when you were compelled to speak.
你可真是一个卑鄙小人!
You are a miserable little man!
嗨, 嗨, 嗨!
Hey, hey, hey!
我们不要在这里浪费时间了, 啊哈?
Let's not ruin the moment here, huh?
好吧, 在我不在的时候
替我看好城市, 嗯?
Now, keep an eye on my city for me,
while I'm gone, hmmm?
祝你好运
Good luck.
好的
好的!
Right.
Right!
MA5-393?
不, 我们只在晚上去过那里
No.
We've only been there at night.
在白天, 那里可是热得不得了
所以, 它不能在候选之列
It's ridiculously hot there during the day,
so no, not really an option.
如果我们选择的阿尔法站点
没有被幽灵做上标记
We wouldn't be having this problem
if the damn Alpha Site that we'd picked,
那么这个就算不上是问题
hadn't been marked by
the Wraith.
它们真是令人心烦, 是不是?
They're a real pain in the ass,
aren't they?
是的
Yes they are.
M4H-212如何?
How about M4H-212?
有Genii的间谍在上面活动
Crawling with Genii spies.
你是确实知道这一点
You know that for a fact SGT?
还是只是你自己的主观臆想?
Or is your spidey sense just tingling.
这是事实, 长官!
It's a fact, sir!
找到一个
M1M-316
Here we go.
M1M-316.
Stackhouse 报告那里的环境很漂亮
而且根据他的队伍所能提供的信息
Stackhouse reported lush surroundings,
and as far as his team could tell,
看起来那里还无人居住
it seemed uninhabited.
我马上集合我的队伍, 去那里查看一下
I'll get my team together and check it out.
OK, 很好
Ok, good.
记住, 少校
我们并不需要十全十美
Remember Major,
we don't need ideal.
我认为只要我们能够在那里居住就行了
I think we'd all settle for close.
我就去!
I'm on it!
少校, Teyla会跟你一起去么?
Major, is Teyla coming with you?
问这个你不会是认真地吧?
You're not seriously asking that?
我认为这是个坏兆头, 长官
I think that's a bad call sir.
你又来了
Here we go again.
我想说的是
我们现在还不能完全了解
All I'm saying is,
we still don't fully understand
她与幽灵之间的联系
以我的建议
her connection to the Wraith,
and in my opinion,
我认为我们不应该
让她接触任何
I don't think we should expose
her to any information
我们不希望幽灵知道的信息
we wouldn't want the Wraith to have.
至少来说, 我们撤退的地点
不能让她知道
Not the least of which,
is the location of our evac site.
Beckett已经检查过了
她完全健康
Doctor Beckett gave her
a clean bill of health.
我也很高兴听到这个, 长官
And that's good to hear sir,
不过如果她不能控制
幽灵如何使用她的...
but if she can't control how
the Wraith use her...
你对那个并不了解
You don't know that.
这就对了, 我们不了解!
That's right, we don't!
她看到了所有幽灵所看到的东西
She saw everything they saw.
谁敢保证它们不能
在她身上做同样的事情呢?
Whose to say they can't
do the same with her.
看到我们所看到的东西
See what we see.
那样的话, 她就会危及到我们的安全
If she's been compromised in any way.
她是我的队伍中的重要一员
不用说了!
She's an integral part
of my team, period!
你的故事结束了!
谈话到此为止!
End of story!
We're done!
这是根据我所获得的信息
所产生的模拟
This is a simulation
I've put together.
它展示了如果我们启动了自毁机制
整座城市将会如何被摧毁
It shows how the city will be destroyed
once we trigger the self destruct.
很高兴你认为我应该来看这个
So glad you felt I need to see this.
我曾经在想, 我的噩梦还不够生动
I was just thinking my nightmares
will be more vivid.
这还不够
It's not going to be enough.
什么?
What?
自毁计划
The self destruct plan.
距离有效实施, 还差得很远
It's nowhere near effective enough.
现在对我来说, 已经相当有效了
Now that seemed pretty
effective to me.
亚特兰蒂斯不仅仅是一座城市
Atlantis is more than just a city.
它是一艘宇宙飞船
It is an intergalactic space craft.
是么?
Yes?
是的, Teyla说过, 幽灵的兴趣
并不在于摧毁亚特兰蒂斯
Yes well, Teyla said the Wraith are not
interested in destroying Atlantis.
他们到这里来是为了去地球
They're coming here to get to Earth.
它们只有通过星际之门才能做到这一点
They can only do that by going
through the Stargate.
这就意味着要劫持这座城市
Which means stealing the city,
这也就是为什么
我们要在这里装上自毁装置
which is why we have
a self destruct in place.
是的, 不过,
如果还有一小块东西可以利用
Yes, but, if they are even
the least bit resourceful,
我必须做这个假设
which I must assume that they are,
它们就可以根据海床上的残骸
很容易的重新设计
they can easily reverse engineer
their own intergalactic engine,
它们自己的星际发动机
from the wreckage on the sea bottom.
这就是说我们要让爆炸更猛烈一些?
So we need a bigger bang?
把它炸成更小的碎片
Break it into smaller pieces.
是的, 那可能会有帮助
Yes well, that would certainly help.
不过我更担心的是古人的数据库
But I'm more concerned about
Ancient database.
它备份数据的能力
It's ability to back up data.
它的冗余度非常高
It's incredibly redundant.
冗余度很高?
Incredibly redundant
这些记录都很老了
That record's old.
不过认真地说, 假如幽灵恢复了
古人的数据库中哪怕是极小的一部分呢?
But seriously, if the Wraith recover even
the smallest part of the Ancient database?
事实上, 这就是我所担心的
That is my concern, exactly.
好吧, 完全摧毁掉数据库
到底有多困难?
Alright, how hard will it be to destroy
all the database terminals?
难以置信的困难
Impossibly hard.
我们必须找到一种方法来
删掉古人的数据据库
We need to figure out
a way to delete the Ancient database.
好啊, 我们可以做到么?
Well, can you do that?
我可以找到
I can find out.
好吧, 找到它
不过在你擦去所有东西之前
Ok, find out, but before
you wipe anything out,
我们必须考虑....
we're gonna have to consider....
Weir博士!
Dr Weir!
什么事?
Yes?
我们收到了一个计划外的外星连接
We have an unscheduled
offworld activation.
Sheppard少校正受到攻击!
Major Sheppard is coming in hot!
发生了什么?
What's going on?
他们遭受到了某种攻击
They ran into some
sort of resistance.
我想是幽灵
I'm thinking Wraith.
幽灵?
Wraith?
你以前不是说过那个星球无人居住么
I thought you said this planet
was uninhabited.
确实是!
It was!
我告诉过你不应该带上她, 长官
I told you she was
a liability sir.
现在, 我不会再允许让你的个人感情
给我们带来其它危险了
Now, I'm not gonna let your personal feelings
endanger this facility, any longer.
什么?
What?
听着, 我并不是在指责你是
有意这样去做的
Look, I'm not accusing
you of doing it intentionally,
不过幽灵一定可以从你那里获取信息
but the Wraith must be getting
information from you.
你到底在说些什么?
What the hell are you talking about?
我们进入了一个....
那到底是什么?
We ran into a....
What the hell was that?
看起来是一个很像T-Rex的恶心的家伙, 长官
(T-Rex是一种恐龙的名字)
It looked an awful lot like
a T-Rex, sir.
是的
T-Rex
Yeah.
T-Rex.
根本就不是幽灵
所以你根本就没有理由来指责
It wasn't even a Wraith,
so why don't you check those accusations.
我认为你并不推荐
把那个星球作为阿尔法站点, 少校
I take it you don't recommend
the planet as an Alpha Site, Major.
它不会是我的第一选择
It wouldn't be my first choice.
如果McKay不能搞好那个卫星
我们就玩完了
If McKay doesn't get the satellite online,
we're screwed.
Weir博士, 我是Miller
我们正在接近那颗卫星
Doctor Weir, this is Miller.
We're approaching the satellite.
你们在这个太阳系的另外一侧
中尉, 你们一定要当心
You're on the other side of the solar system,
Lt. You guys be careful out there.
明白
Understood
OK, 关上隔离门
OK, close the bulkhead doors.
祝你好运
Good luck.
Right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
Bates军士!
SGT Bates!
什么事?
What is it?
你刚才指责我将我们的位置
报告给了幽灵
You just accused me of disclosing
our position to the Wraith.
是的!
Yes I did!
很明显你错了
Clearly you were wrong.
这仍然需要证实, 女士
That's yet to be determined ma'am.
抱歉?
Excuse me?
听着, 我情愿相信你不能完全控制
你所泄漏出去的那些信息
Look. I'm willing to accept that you're not fully
in control of what information you give away,
不过我仍然认为
but it's still my opinion that
you should not be
你不应被允许在这个基地自由走动
allowed to move freely around
this base of operations.
也许你并不是十分清楚
不过被指责为幽灵服务
Perhaps you are not aware SGT,
but being accused of serving
在我的人民当中是最大的侮辱
the Wraith is the greatest insult
among my people.
噢, 我清楚
Oh I'm aware.
到底发生什么了?
What the hell's going on?
我只是想表明一个观点, 少校!
I was simply stating an opinion, Major!
她袭击我!
She attacked me!
以一个很正当的理由!!
And for good reason!!
好啊, 那到底是什么理由啊?
Yeah, and what reason would that be?
我想可能是幽灵吧!
My guess would be the Wraith!
滚开, Bates
Walk away Bates.
长官!
Sir!
滚开!
Walk away!
这还没完!
This isn't over!
如果是, 那才令人失望呢
I would be disappointed if it were.
你到底在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
你并没有去检查安全领班!
You don't go around decking
the head of security!
他说....
He said....
我不管他说了些什么!
他说了很多东西
I don't care what he said!
He say's a lot of things.
你最好离他远一点
You just stay away from him.
你还好吧?
Are you ok?
是的, 怎么了?
Yes, why?
你的呼吸非常沉重
You're breathing pretty heavily.
是的, 我只是对这个狭小的地方有些不适应
Yes well, I feel a little claustrophobic.
这些东西里面有多少空气?
How much air do these things hold,
anyways?
八个小时
Eight hours.
那足够了, 是吧?
我的意思是, 即便是沉重的呼吸的话
Well that's enough, right?
I mean, even with heavy breathing.
他们把那也算进去了, 是不是?
They would calculate that in, right?
你不会有事的
You're going to be fine.
是的, 你说起来容易
Yeah, it's easy for you to say.
你并不用担心
自己只能呼吸八个小时
You're not the one with
the eight hour ceiling of breathing.
它已经完全死掉了
It's completely dead.
是的, 我们已经考虑到了
Well, we thought as much.
我准备接上naquadah发电机
I'm gonna hook up the naquadah generator.
看看能不能让一些
生命支持系统工作起来
See if I can get some life
support going.
Halling, 你好
Halling, hello.
我们可以说几句么?
May we speak?
当然, 请坐吧
Please, have a seat.
大陆上的撤退工作准备得怎么样了?
How is the evacuation
on the mainland coming?
我们会准备好的
We'll be ready.
很好
Good.
Weir博士, 我们听到有人说
你们准备摧毁亚特兰蒂斯?
Dr Weir, word is there
is a plan in place to destroy Atlantis.
我们有些顾虑
There are concerns.
如果这个城市仍然完好的话
幽灵就可以通过它去地球
The Wraith would be able to make it
to Earth if the city is left intact.
不过我想你保证, 这只是我们在
最坏的情况下的打算
But I assure you, that plan would only
be executed in a worst case scenario.
比如三艘幽灵的母船
向亚特兰蒂斯飞来?
Such as three hive ships flying
towards Atlantis?
我们相信我们可以在他们到达之前
摧毁它们
We do believe we'll be able to
destroy them before they arrive.
我理解你很担心你的人民
I understand you fearing for the
well being of your people,
不过这并不是摧毁祖先城市的理由
but it is not reason to destroy
the city of the ancestors.
亚特兰蒂斯是一个神圣的地方
Atlantis is a sacred place.
如果只是为了保存你们自己
就想到摧毁它的话....
To even consider destroying it,
merely for self preservation....
只是为了保存自己?
Merely for self preservation?
这个地方是那个曾经存在于多个星球的
最伟大的种族唯一所剩下的东西
This place is all that remains of the greatest
race ever to inhabit the stars.
你更想让它落入幽灵之手么?
And you would prefer it fell into
the hands of the Wraith?
我相信祖先们不会让这发生的
I would have faith that the ancestors
would not allow it to happen.
他们已经让亚特兰蒂斯保存了亿万年
你认为这没有可能么?
They have been able to preserve Atlantis
for 10,000 years. Is it not possible?
是的, 我认为这是不可能的
No, I don't think it is possible.
如果你在设想古人会及时回来
拯救他们的城市, 我认为这是不可能的
Not if you're suggesting the Ancients
will return in time to save their city.
你并不知道他们关于亚特兰蒂斯的计划
You cannot know their plans for Atlantis.
他们已经做好了他们所能够做出的
所有的计划
They have made all the plans
they are going to make.
现在轮到我们了
Now it's up to us.
我很感谢你的想法, Halling,
不过我会尽一切可能
I thank you for your thoughts Halling,
but I have to do everything
来保证亚特兰蒂斯的能量和技术
I can to make sure the power
and technology of Atlantis,
不会落入幽灵之手
does not fall into the hands
of the Wraith,
并保证它们不会进入我的星系
and yes, to ensure they never make
it to my galaxy.
即便这意味着要牺牲这里的未来?
Even if it means sacrificing
the future of this one?
你知道
想法非常简单
You know,
the idea is simple enough.
执行起来确是非常困难
The execution is proving
to be very difficult.
制作病毒?
Creating the virus?
基本上说, 是这样
Essentially, yes.
一个古老而简单的计算机病毒
一旦被引入这个系统
A plain old computer virus,
once introduced into the system,
就会把数据库擦得干干净净
wiped the database clean.
它可以作为自毁机制倒计时程序的
一部分而被下载
It could be downloaded
as part of the self destruct countdown.
甚至还有可能影响幽灵的系统
如果它们试图访问的话
Might even affect the Wraiths systems
if they tried to access it.
我们可以保留下多少?
How much of it can we save?
抱歉?
I'm sorry?
数据库中的信息
Of the database.
我们带来了很多硬盘
Now we brought a lot of hard drives with us.
我们可以转移多少到我们的计算机上?
How much can we transfer
to our computers?
你的意思是像, 备份?
我们带走一个备份?
You mean like, back it up?
Take a copy with us?
是的, 是这样
Yes, exactly.
采用McKay的压缩算法
我可以说, 可能7%, 或许8%
Using McKay's compression code,
I'd say, maybe 7, maybe 8%.
就这些?
That's it?
是的
Yes.
好了!
Here we go!
主电源启动
Primary power online.
看起来生命支持系统现在已经是100%了
我认为我找到了启动重力的开关了
Looks like life supports now at 100%.
I think I found the switch to initialise the gravity.
很好, 给我一小会儿时间....
Great, just give me a second to....
噢, 好, 好的!
我的后背看起来是永久性的损伤了
Oh yep. Yep!
That's permanent back damage.
我很抱歉, 我本以为没有这么快的
I'm sorry, I assumed it would come
on more slowly.
你的假设差点要了我的命
Well you assumed with my life.
你会没事的, 这只是一个小碰撞
You'll be fine, it was just a little bump.
如果换成是你呢?
What have you got?
看起来每个系统都重新运作起来了
除了武器系统
Looks like every system is back online,
except for the weapon.
详细信息
我们开始工作吧
Details.
Let's get to work.
谢谢, 谢谢!
Thankyou.
Thankyou!
是脊柱的损伤, 我记得这种疼痛
Oh, yeah. That's vertabrae damage.
I recognise the pain.
M1K-439怎样?
How about M1K-439?
那是什么?
Which one's that?
到处都是瀑布的那个?
The one with all the waterfalls?
瀑布
The waterfalls.
瞧, 我们为什么不叫它
瀑布行星?
See now, why don't we just
call it Planet Waterfall?
什么?
我说我们应该为它们命名
What?
I say we should just give them names.
我们现在已经列出了五个行星了
Look, we've got a list
of five planets here.
可以让Stackhouse和他的队伍
出发去检查一下了
That should be enough potential Alpha Sites
to get Stackhouse and his team started.
(广播)少校, 一号发电机出现了一些情况
What's up.
发生什么了
It's Bates sir.
是Bates, 长官
What about him?
- 他怎么了?
- 他被袭击了
He's been attacked.
叫一支医疗队到这里来
Get a medical team down here.
他会没事么?
Is he gonna be ok?
还很难说
It's still hard to tell.
他断了五根肋骨, 和一根锁骨
He's got five broken ribs,
a fractured collarbone,
而且脑震荡也非常厉害
and the concussion was quite severe.
什么时候可以跟他说话?
When can we talk to him?
不行
我用药物把他维持在昏迷状态
We can't.
I put him in a medically induced coma,
直到脑膜下的血肿可以被处理
until the subdural haematoma
can be deal't with.
现阶段, 我们还无法知道
在他身上到底发生了什么
We won't be finding what happened
from him, anytime soon.
Teyla和Bates昨天搞得非常僵, 长官
Teyla and Bates got into
it pretty bad yesterday sir.
殴打成这样, 就是另外一回事了, Ford
A fistfight and a beating like this,
are a long drive apart, Ford.
我知道, 长官
不过他们确实打过架
I understand that sir,
but they were in a fight
而且他们都不愿意停止
and they were both looking
to continue it.
有没有迹象证明是谁做的?
Anything pointing
to who did this?
我正准备检查他的身体和衣服
马上就开始
I'm having a forensic exam of both
his body and clothing, performed right now.
如果找到了马上告诉我们
让我们去听听她会怎么说
Let us know what you find out.
Let's go get her side of the story.
这不是发电机的问题
Well, it's not a power
generation problem.
naquadah产出的能量已经绰绰有余了
The naquadah's pumping
out more than enough juice.
那为什么它不启动呢?
Well then why isn't it?
好吧, 让我们从头开始, 好好想想
Ok, alright. Let's just step back
here and think about it.
这个家伙是一个定向能量波武器
This baby is a directed energy
beam weapon.
由相对较低的能源
如我们的naquadah发电机, 充电
然后一下子释放出来
Runs off a relatively low yield charge,
like our naquadah generator,
这就是说它必须通过某种缓冲器
或者是一个电容器, 持续充电
so that means it's gotta be continually
building up a charge
直到被放电为止
with some kind of a buffer,
or a capacitor, until it's discharged.
我认为我找到了某种类似的东西
I think I found something like that.
是的, 就是它
现在缓冲器的水平是90%
Yes, here it is.
Right now the buffer's at 90%.
Ok. 这么说电能是流到了缓冲器中了
而不是直接流到世纪的武器中
Ok. So power's getting to the buffer,
it's just not getting to the actual weapon.
让我看看能不找到某种诊断程序
Let me see if I can find
a diagnostics programme.
这里一定有
There must be one here.
Ok, 我们还剩下29小时
Ok, we got 29 hours till showtime,
因此希望我们不要回去拿东西, 嗯?
so let's hope we don't have to
order parts, huh?
你并不认为我跟这有关?
You do not think
I had anything to do with it?
当然不
Of course not.
你和Bates昨天确实处得很糟
You and Bates did get into
it pretty good yesterday.
你了解我, Aiden
我从来不会做得那么过分的
You know me, Aiden.
I never would have taken it that far.
我知道, 所以让我们看看
我们能不能一起把这件事搞清楚
I know, so let's just see if
we can't rule it out, altogether.
你昨天晚上在哪里?
Where were you last night?
我在这里, 我的房间中
I was here in my room
整个晚上都是?
The whole night?
是的
Yes
这么说没有办法知道你是不是出去了
So there's no way of knowing whether
you blacked out or not.
我没有办法证明, 是的!
I have no way of proving it, no!
不过昨天晚上我没有离开这个房间
我保证
But I did not leave this room last night,
I am sure of it.
我没有离开这个房间
I did not leave this room
你要见我?
You asked to see me?
Stackhouse 找到了
一个合适的阿尔法站点
Stackhouse has found
a suitable Alpha Site,
因此一旦需要的话
我们就能够撤离了
so should the need arise,
we'll be able to evacuate.
噢, 那很好
Oh, that's good.
这并不是我想见你的原因
That's not why
I wanted to see you.
你必须想办法备份超过7%或者8%
的数据库信息
You have to get me more than seven
or eight percent of the database.
我们一定有办法带走更多
There has got to be a way
of taking more with us.
也许9%
Maybe nine percent.
那么我是应该选择备份
零点模块研究
How do I choose between
Zero Point Module
还是他们关于升天方面的资料呢?
research and their work on ascension.
是备份武器的图纸呢
还是他们关于星际旅行的笔记?
I mean, between weapons schematics
and their notes on space travel.
无论我们如何选择
都将会失去很多无价的信息
No matter what we choose here,
invaluable information's gonna be lost,
而这些只是我们解密了的信息
and that is just the information
we've deciphered.
现在我们都知道
我们甚至都还没有钻透它们的表皮
Now we all know we have barely even
begun to scratch the surface.
假如我们毁掉的是
治愈所有疾病的药方
What if we destroy
the cure for all disease,
甚至于是某条可以引导我们
打败幽灵的信息呢?
or even some piece of information that could
lead to the downfall of the Wraith.
我不知道该跟你说些什么
I don't know what I can tell you.
我会努力提高McKay的压缩算法的压缩比
I will try to improve on
McKay's compression ratio's,
不过我们是在面临战争, Elizabeth
有战争就有伤亡
but we are at war Elizabeth.
In war there are casualties.
啊, 谁来看看这些图表?
Ah, schematics, anyone?
看起来能量在内部流动
从缓冲器到武器
It looks like power runs internally,
from the buffer to the weapon.
我想在它到达的时候
I guess when it took a hit,
它一定会扰动主能量管道
it must have disrupted
the main power conduit.
我们需要变更路线
让能量从我们的缓冲器
We need to reroute
the power from our buffer
到武器中去
to the actual to the actual weapon.
如果我们做到这一点, 武器就准备好了
If we can do that, it will arm.
知道么, 你说的这些是人都明白
You know, your masterful grip
on the blatantly obvious,
继续说话打动我, Peter
continues to impress me, Peter.
谢谢
Thankyou
好吧. 我们需要引导能量
绕过这些损坏的线路
Alright. We need to route power around
these damaged circuits.
如果我们做到了, 那就可以好好轻松一下了
好吧, 我现在完全分不清了
If we do that, we should be laughing.
Alright, I'm disoriented.
这些在哪里?
Where are these?
它们在外面
They're outside.
什么?
What?
瞧
Look.
看到了?
See?
哦!
Oh great!
必须有人去进行太空行走
Someone will need to EVA.
那里没有地方可以挂住
There's nothing to hang onto.
我没有说这很容易和安全
I'm not saying it'll be easy or safe.
Ok. 那么谁去?
Ok. So who goes?
好吧, 我们可以抽麦秆
Well, we could draw straws.
Ok Miller, 去准备"麦秆"吧!
Ok Miller, break out the straws!
没有必要抽麦秆
It doesn't have to be straws.
我们可以石头剪刀布
We could do rock,
paper, scissors.
好吧, 三个人
一, 二, 三
Ok, on three.
One, two, three.
Ok, 很明显, 石头剪刀布
并不适合三个人玩
Ok, obviously Rock, Paper, Scissors,
doesn't work with three.
有人有铅笔么?
Anyone have a pencil?
是的, 我想我有一支
Yeah, I think I've got one.
好吧, 准备吧
Well, get on with it.
Ok. 谁抽到短的那根, 谁就去
Ok. Short piece goes.
你先
You go first.
嗯, 很好, 你的很不错
Mmm. Well done.
Good for you.
Miller?
是的
Yeah.
不管怎么说, 你最有资格去修好它
You're the best qualified to fix it,
anyway sir.
嗯, 一次死亡之旅
好吧
Mmmm. Flight of the dead man.
Good.
我知道她和Bates都彼此憎恨着对方
I know there's no love lost
between her and Bates,
不过我并不认为是她打了那个家伙
but I can't see her beating
the hell out of the guy.
Ford?
女士?
Ma'am?
你认为呢?
What do you think?
我担心她可能是在
不知不觉中去做的
I worry about what she might
have done, unknowingly.
那些与幽灵的连接
The whole Wraith connection thing
以及她的恶梦, 都让我很紧张
and her nightmares,
make me nervous.
是的, 那我们应该怎么做呢
Yeah well,
what are we gonna do about it,
把她钉到桅杆上?
我们在谈论的是Teyla啊
stick her in the brig? This is Teyla we're talking about.
我们的人有麻烦了
We have a situation on our hands.
怎么了?
What's going on?
我已经完成了检验
我在Bates军事的制服上找到了DNA
I've completed the tests.
I found DNA in SGT Bates' uniform.
那不是Teyla的
And it's not Teyla's.
不是的, 少校
No Major.
是谁的?
Who is it?
为了确定, 我检验了两次
结果是决定性的
I ran the test twice to be certain.
It's conclusive.
在我们的城市中有一个幽灵
We have a Wraith in the city.
这怎么可能啊?
怎么可能有幽灵进入到城市中来?
Can someone tell me how this is possible?
How can a Wraith get inside the city?
不是通过星际之门进来的
They didn't gate in.
那艘梭镖飞船
The dart.
什么?
What?
那艘幽灵的梭镖飞船扫描了我们
The Wraith dart that scanned us.
它穿过了城市上空
扫描以获取数据
It made it's way through the city,
scanning for data.
在它完成的那一刻
它就自毁了
The second it was done,
it self destructed.
这么说它通过光柱潜入到了城市
So he beamed into the city
它们可以做到么?
Can they do that?
这跟将人们吸进它们的飞船
所用的技术相同
The same technology that is used
to sweep people up into their ships,
只是工作的方向相反
must work in the opposite way.
就是说幽灵梭镖飞船的飞行员
扫描了我们
So the pilot of the Wraith dart
scanned us,
把得到的信息传送给了母船
transmitted his information
to the hive ships,
通过光柱下到这里
然后毁掉了它的飞船
beamed down here
and destroyed his ship.
是的, 是的, 看起来是可能的
Yes, yes.
Seem's possible.
正好就是在那时起
我就开始不断的感觉到了幽灵
That is precisely the time
I started to sense the Wraith continually.
难怪你总是在做恶梦
No wonder you were having nightmares.
这些时候, 它都在这里做什么?
What's he been doing here, all this time?
Bates军士在为控制台提供能量的
Well, SGT Bates was attacked near
naquadah发电机旁边受到袭击
the naquadah generator
that powers this tower.
它的任务应该是过来侦查
His brief must have been
during recon.
也许它的任务是
在母船到达这里的时候切断电源
Maybe his job is to knock out the power
before the hive ship get's here.
让我们死在水中
Leave us dead in the water.
或者让我们以前所制定的自毁计划
无法工作
Or to make sure any self destruct plan
we had in place, wouldn't work.
也许是两者兼而有之
Maybe a combination of both.
很对
Exactly.
我们现在能够确信的是
What we do know for sure,
is that we have
在我们的城市中有一个幽灵入侵者
我们必须找到它
a Wraith intruder in the city,
that we have to track down.
我有办法
I have an idea.
我们离开了
We're away.
在不到三十米远的地方
It's not much more than
thirty metres away.
我们已经就位了, 先生
We're in position sir.
好的, Miller
我要你打开通风孔
Ok Miller. I want you to vent
the atmosphere and disengage
并且解除后部舱室的人工重力
the artificial gravity
in the rear compartment.
Ok, 打开后舱门
Ok, open the rear hatch.
噢, 我的...
Oh my
Rodney?
Rodney, 你到了么?
Rodney, did you make it?
我还没有离开飞船的尾部
I haven't quite left the rear
of the Jumper yet.
需要我提醒你时间么?
Do I need to remind you
of the time?
是的, 提醒我吧
我们的时间很紧吧?
Yes, please do.
Remind me, are we on a tight schedule?
显而易见
Just pointing out the obvious.
Ok, 谢谢
我的一小步, 啊?
Ok, thankyou.
One small step, huh?
人类的一大步!
One giant leap!
抱歉?
I'm sorry?
我到了
I made it.
很好
Good.
先看看这第一个面板
Let's take a look at this first panel.
这是我们大约一个月前启动的
生物探测器
This is a biometric sensor we've had
online for the past month or so.
它检查不规则的生物频率
It detects irregularities
in biometric rhythm,
然后进行报告
and reports them.
那它为什么没有报告那个幽灵?
Wouldn't it have picked
up on the Wraith?
它需要大量的能量
因此我们缩小了它的探测范围
It requires significant amount of power,
so we've narrowed it's field of focus,
只让它探测星际之门控制室了
to scan solely in the gateroom,
本来是想幽灵或者其他外星人
figuring that was the only
place that the Wraith
只能从那里进入城市
or any other alien for that matter,
would likely enter the city from.
Ok, 现在这种看法是错的了
Ok, so that was wrong.
是的. 现在如果我把范围扩展到...
Yeah. Now if I could only
expand the field to...
我的天!
My God!
什么?
What?
那就是它
看!
That's him.
Look!
它的工作原理非常类似于生命信号探测器
不过它可以区分不同的生命形式
It works very much like the life signs detector,
but it's able to distinguish different lifeforms.
是它
It's him
你可以实时跟踪它
You can track him in real time.
是的
Yes
Ford, Teyla, 我们需要两队人
我们去抓住它
Ford, Teyla, we need two teams.
Let's go get him.
是的, 长官!
Yes sir!
很糟糕, 非常糟糕
我不知道我能不能修好它
This is bad, very bad.
I'm not sure I can fix this.
你可以修好任何东西
You can fix anything.
谁告诉你的?
Who told you that?
你已经做过几次了
You did on several occasions.
好吧, 你是对的
Well you're right.
那可能是件好事
我抽到了最短的麦秆
It's probably a good thing
I drew the short straw.
差不多是这样
That's more like it.
主电力管道已经被严重损坏了
The main power conduit's been severed.
我也许有办法可以变更路线
There may be some way
for me to reroute it,
让它通过副管道
so that it's going through
secondary conduits.
就像是一种旁路那样
Sort of like a quadruple bypass.
我在这里应该可以帮助你
标出一个潜在的副管道
I should be able to help you identify
a potential secondary conduits from here.
我们的时间只够尝试一次
We're only going to have enough time
to try this once.
让我们开始吧
Let's get started.
它还在那里么, 博士?
Is he still in place, Doc?
是的, 它还在那个房间里
自从我们找到之后就没有动过
Yes, he's still in the same room.
Hasn't moved since we located him.
希望它还在睡觉
Ford, Teyla, 你们就位了么?
Let's hope he's still sleeping.
Ford, Teyla, you in position?
快了
Almost.
我的队伍已经准备好了
My team's ready.
我们准备同时从不同的方向
冲进那个房间
We're going to breach the room
at the same time from different directions.
如果它试图从另外一个门出去
抓住它
If he tries to get out the other door, take him.
明白
Understood sir.
我们两分钟后就到
We shouldn't be more than
a couple of minutes.
很好, 准备行动
Alright, stand by.
Ok, 我在这能做的就是这些了
能量过去了么?
Ok, that's all I can do from here.
Is power getting through?
是的, 能量已经过去了
Yes, the power is getting through.
噢, 感谢上帝!
好了, 我准备结束这次太空行走
Oh thank God!
Ok, I'm gonna end this EVA.
我回到飞船, 我们把你带上
然后我们离开这里
I'm coming in,we're gonna pick you up
and get the hell out of here.
听起来像是一个计划
Sounds like a plan, sir.
好吧
Alright.
没有什么可以阻止我们
前往我们的新取食场
Nothing will keep us
from our new feeding ground.
我们都听到了, 长官
You were on vox, sir.
我们听到了一切
然后快步赶了过来
We heard the whole thing
and double timed it.
我们抓住它了, 少校
你会没事的
We got him Major.
You're gonna be ok.
Peter, 我们没法停靠到卫星上
Peter, we're having trouble docking
with the satellite.
看看你那边能够做些什么
See what you can do
from your side.
哦, 想起来了
Oh dear.
想起来什么?
Oh dear, what?
当我们改变能量从缓冲区到武器的线路时
When we rerouted the power from
the buffer to the weapon,
看起来好像我们不经意间
把通往停靠站和气闸盖的能量也引开了
it looks like we inadvertantly routed power
away from the docking station and the air lock.
这会是个问题
That's going to be a problem.
Ok, 我们手动操作
就像我们第一次做的那样
Ok, we'll do it manually,
like we did the first time.
第一次你有太空服, 而我现在没有
打开气闸盖会使舱内失压
You had a spacesuit the first time, I don't.
The airlock isn't pressurised.
那么我们... 听着,
我会回去重新改变能量线路
Then we'll... Look,
I'll go back and reroute the power.
没时间了
幽灵的飞船已经很近了
There isn't time for that.
The Wraith ships are too close.
我知道我在做什么
I know what I'm doing now.
Rodney.
别管我
Leave me.
我们不会这样做的
We're not doing that.
飞到安全距离之外
然后在卫星教训完幽灵的飞船之后
Get to a safe distance,
and then come get me once
再回来接我
the satellite has taken care
of the Wraith ships.
Peter.
这是唯一的选择
你知道的
It's the only option
and you know it.
另外, 这样我也可以先关掉卫星
Besides, this way
I can power down the satellite,
直到它们都进入了射程再打开
until they're well within range.
这样幽灵就不会知道
Then there'll be no way
for the Wraith
我们已经让它重新运转起来了
to realise that we've brought
it back online.
好吧, 我们会隐形
然后在结束后回来接你
Alright, we'll cloak and come back
for you after it's done.
在这结束之后
After it's done then.
很高兴看到你又能站起来了, 长官
感觉怎么样?
Good to see you on your feet sir.
How are you feeling?
有些发麻和刺痛
被那些东西击昏之后都有这个感觉
You know, pins and needles.
Getting stung by those damn things.
它说了什么没有?
Has he said anything yet?
没有, 长官, 还没有
No sir, not yet.
你有名字么?
You got a name?
Ok, 我们就叫你Bob吧, Bob
Ok, we'll go with Bob, Bob,
我想知道, 过去两个星期
I'm gonna need to know what
you've been doing
你都在这里做了些什么
现在就想知道
here for the past two weeks and
I'm going to need to know now.
如果你还没有启动
现在应该是时候了
If you're not already powered up,
now would be a good time.
正在启动!
Powering up!
我们在60秒后就可以预热好武器
We should be weapons
hot in 60 seconds.
Weir博士, 我是McKay
卫星已经准备好战斗了
Dr Weir, it's McKay.
The satellite is armed and ready.
它大约可以在一分钟内射击
It should fire within
the next minute or so.
等着看好戏吧
Keep your fingers crossed.
我们在等!
祝好运!
Fingers crossed!
Good luck!
我想他现在没有心情说话, 长官
I don't think he's in
a very talkative mood, sir.
我想知道它做了些什么
I need to know what he's been
doing and whether
以及它是否正在向母船传送信息
or not he's been transferring
data to the hive ships.
我们无法截获这种传输么?
Wouldn't we have picked
up the transmission?
我们可以发送加密信息
没有理由它不能这样做
We can send secure messages,
there's no reason he can't.
也许我可以试着跟它建立连接
Maybe I can try and connect
with him.
我不这样认为
I don't think so.
如果阿尔法站点已经被发现了, 少校
If the Alpha Site has been
compromised Major,
我们需要知道
we need to know.
好吧, 看看你能做些什么
Ok, see what you can do.
从手动模式切换到自动开火模式
就绪!
Switching over from manual
to automatic firing mode. Stand by!
就绪
Standing by.
我们已经干掉一艘了!
We have a kill!
我们收到了, Rodney
We copy that, Rodney.
打下了一艘, 还有两艘
One down, two to go.
你在做什么, 人类?
What are you doing, human?
你正在试图进入我的意识
You're trying to get inside my mind.
允许我!
Allow me!
Teyla? 停下来!
你在做什么?
Teyla? Stop it!
What are you doing?
你还好吧?
Are you ok?
我身上的创伤会自动恢复
My wounds will heal.
是的, 不过要多久?
Yeah, but for how long?
我要知道你对这个城市做了些什么
I need to know what
you've done to this city.
听着Bob, 不管怎样
我都可以轻松的杀死你
Listen Bob. I have no problem
with killing you, whatsoever.
快点, 快点
再次出击啊!
Come on, come on.
Hit em again!
我们有问题了!
We have a problem!
什么, 什么问题?
What, what problem?
看起来好像是
我们改线之后的发送器过载了
It looks like the sender
we rerouted has overloaded.
武器不能再次发射了
我正试图寻找其它的方法
The weapon can't fire again.
I'm trying to find another pathway.
我们就回来接你
We're heading back in to pick you up.
呆在原地别动!
Stay exactly where you are!
我们已经隐形了, 它们不会看到我们的!
Look, we're cloaked,
they won't see us!
没有时间了
快点离开这里!
There's no time,
just get the hell out of here!
我很抱歉!
I'm sorry!
把我们带回到卫星那里去
Get us back to that satellite.
噢, 天哪!
Oh God!
我不是在跟你浪费时间, Bob!
你到底对这个基地采取了破坏行动没有?
I'm not screwing around Bob!
Did you sabotage this base or not?
那些从你身上取食的幽灵
将会知道你对我所做的一切
Those who feed upon you,
will know what you've done to me.
是的, 那我们来看看吧
Yeah, we'll see.
长官! 我想我们也许有点过头了
Sir! I think maybe we've gone a bit too far.
我认为我们还做得不够
I don't think we've gone far enough.
亚特兰蒂斯, 我是McKay!
我们已经失去了卫星!
Atlantis, this is McKay!
We have lost the satellite!
你们有没有打下更多的飞船?
Did you manage to take
out any more ships?
没有, 另外两艘飞船都完好无损
Negative. The two other
hive ships are intact.
Elizabeth, Peter Grodin
当时正在卫星上
was aboard the satellite.
明白
另外两艘是什么状态?
Understood.
What's the status of the other two?
它们没有继续靠近了
They're not coming any closer.
看起来好像它们在重新考虑它们的计划
Looks like they're rethinking
their plans.
至少来说, 他为我们带来更多的时间
At the very least,
he's bought us some time.
你在那儿也做不了什么了, Rodney
返回亚特兰蒂斯吧
You can't do anymore out there Rodney.
Return to Atlantis.
正回来
On our way
我要对整个城市讲话
Put me on city wide.
各位请注意
我是Weir博士
May I have your attention please.
This is Doctor Weir.
我们阻止幽灵舰队的计划失败了
Our plan to stop
the Wraith Armada, has failed.
它们会直取亚特兰蒂斯
They will make it to Atlantis.
因此, 我们必须开始我们的撤退计划
Therefore, we must begin
our evacuation plans.
我希望我能够告诉你们
这是一场我们可以打赢的战争
I wish I could tell you all that this
is a fight that we will win,
可是我做不到
but I can't do that.
我希望我可以告诉你们, 到我们离开
这里时, 我们可以找到一个安全的避风港
I wish I could tell you that we will find
a safe harbour when we leave here.
这个我也不能向你们保证
我能够告诉你们的是
I can't promise you that either.
I can tell you this.
直到现在为止
你们大家都已经实现了非凡的成就
Up till now, you all have accomplished
extraordinary things,
并且我确信
即使是面对无法确定的未来
and I believe that even in
the face of an uncertain future,
只要我们团结在一起
我们就还有生存的希望
as long as we stay together we have
a chance to continue to do so.
现在, 我们都有撤退的职责
Now, we all have
our evacuation duties.
谢谢你们
我会在另外一边见到你们
So thankyou,
and I'll see you on the other side.
Zelenka博士?
把病毒程序准备好
Doctor Zelenka?
Put the virus programme on standby.
我告诉你们
不管你们逃到哪里, 我们都会找到你们
I will tell you this.
No matter where you flee, we will find you.
就跟我们一定会找到地球一样
Just as surely as we will find Earth.
到那时, 我们会进行一次盛宴
And when we do, we will feast.
未完待续
StarGate Atlantis
1x19 - The Siege